ADAM PARSONS

3600 Conshohocken avenue, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19131 | (C) 8562831098 | parsons.adamj@gmail.com

Summary

High performing sales professional effective at managing and leading teams, maximizing productivity, and developing strategies to boost sales. Currently seeking a career change with an organization that will enable us to grow together by leveraging my well-developed skills earned through over twenty years of fast paced, high volume sales team leadership.

Skills

- Staff training and development
- Strategic thinking
- Team Building

- Tradeshow Planning
- New Account Acquisition
- Competitive Analysis

Work History

Park Director 01/2019 to current

StoneMor Partners LP – Plymouth Meeting, PA

- Managed a team of four counselors in a traditionally under producing location and worked closely with them to implement new initiatives and policies.
- Participated in hiring and training of new sales counselors to invigorate and disrupt existing culture. All new hires exceeded regional average for percent to budget, appointments set, and closing ratio for Q1 2019.
- Worked closely with local funeral homes to repair relationships damaged by competing priorities.
 Started monthly luncheon round table to network and discuss opportunities for mutually beneficial strategies.
- Achieved 170% of target budget for Q1 2019. Sole location in region of over 60 parks with a budget of greater than \$50,000 to achieve greater than %100 of target budget for the same period.
- Generated revenue of over \$450,000 for Q1 2019 against a previous performance of \$210,000 for the same period in 2018.
- Integrated previously under-utilized CRM into daily sales philosophy to both develop clearly outlined sales goals and hold counselors accountable. Increased participation in lead, appointment, and call tracking from under %20 to over %95.

District Sales Director 09/2017 to 01/2019

StoneMor Partners LP - Plymouth Meeting, PA

• Successfully managed a team of six locations including branch managers and sales counselors in a high volume environment resulting in a projected annual growth of over twenty-five percent in net revenue.

- Outperformed percent to goal for national and regional quotas by bringing a fresh approach to a traditionally formulaic sales process and targeting demographics previously believed to be unprofitable.
- Engaged local communities to establish reciprocal marketing agreements and arrange for direct engagement opportunities through table days and branded offers resulting in double digit market share growth.
- Streamlined and digitized several outdated processes at the park level to allow counselors to fluidly react to changing job demands.
- Aggressively recruited new talent from unconventional candidate pools such as service industry
 workers and retail sales people to revitalize a stagnant work force, reducing previous employee
 ninety day turnover rate from twenty-five to eight percent.
- Designed templates to address common pain points in the sales process and fill in gaps with current company offerings.
- Recognized as regional "MVP" for Q2 and Q3 of 2018.

Retail Store Manager 06/2013 to 09/2017

T-Mobile - Upper Darby, PA

- Responsible for short and long term operations of store on a daily basis. Duties included coaching
 and scheduling of employees, maintaining inventory and merchandising of location, and
 accountability for store performance as a whole.
- Developed and implemented business to business program to prospect, educate, and close potential corporate accounts. Cross trained existing associates to properly manage opportunities in company CRM software and funnel leads from existing customer base.
- Drove growth in measured areas consistently, regularly outperforming the district in key revenue metrics with verifiable results. Increased net activation attainment by over thirty percent in first month as store manager of a new location.
- Participated in several stretch assignments at the district level to build competencies in multi-unit management including hosting weekly conference calls, store visits to identify and coach in areas of opportunity, and organizing and staffing outreach events.
- Designed and implemented suite of tools to facilitate performance tracking, customer follow up, and pricing comparison used in multiple regions.
- Cultivated retail sales associates to further personal careers and growth, including one of two district candidates for 2015 through 2017 career development and mentorship program.
- Tasked with identifying customers' accounts desirable to leverage current promotions, developing sales strategy, and disseminating standardized approach to the district. Developed system of accountability at district level to effectively meet deadlines and create team cohesion.
- Recognized for leading one of the top ten performing stores in the Greater Philadelphia region for Q1 2015 through Q1 2017. Most recent recipient award for top performing location in Philadelphia West district. District "How We Play Value's Leader" for 2015.

Co-Owner 03/2012 to 06/2013

Network Wireless - Bordentown, NJ

Planned and developed a third party retail location from inception to opening. Responsible for all
facets of store operations including site selection and leasing, implementation of POS systems,
negotiating vendor agreements, and ordering and installation of store fixtures to corporate
standards.

- Hired and trained team of employees including managers, sales associates, and technicians. Ensured all employees attended and completed mandatory trainings and obtained certifications.
- Marketed company using both social and direct campaigns. Networked with local business owners and established reciprocal offers within community to drive traffic.
- Handled company financials and analyzed business trends. Managed all payroll payments, vendor invoices, utility payments, and device payments against thirty day net terms.
- Tracked inventory and reviewed receipts for discrepancies. Monitored profit and loss to consistently stay ahead of business fluctuations and account for expected future revenue.
- Negotiated and secured eventual sale of company, facilitating transition of leasing agreement, software licensing, payroll, and credit terms to new owner.

Retail Store Manager 11/2009 to 03/2012

I-Mobile - Philadelphia, PA

- Responsible for daily operations and management of store.
- Directed all operations of sales associates and resolved customer escalations. Assigned employees to specific duties to best meet the needs of the store.
- Exceeded required goals for customer satisfaction index and total handset sales.
- Ordered and accounted for all handset and accessory merchandise. Increased profits through effective sales training and troubleshooting profit loss areas.
- Assured regular upkeep of planograms to be compliant with corporate layout. Examined merchandise to verify that it was correctly priced and displayed.
- Multiple times recipient of award for top store in overall performance.

Retail Store Manager 06/2002 to 11/2009

VIP Wireless – Burlington, NJ

- Responsible for ordering inventory, making bank deposits, resolving scheduling conflicts, and hiring and training of all sales associates.
- Regularly met assigned store quotas in all categories and consistently doubled personal quotas.
- Managed top producing store in all franchise locations for three consecutive years.
- Designed paperwork consolidation process utilized companywide to reduce churn and charge back exposure.
- Achieved certification as Sprint technician capable of diagnosing and repairing handsets.
- Hired, trained and evaluated personnel in sales and marketing.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering **Stevens Institute of Technology** - Hoboken, NJ

Attended from 2000 through 2002.

Coursework included Physics, Organic Chemistry, Mechanics of Solids, Switching Theory, and Calculus.